Faith evolves.
Creation is a drama, history film directed by Jon Amiel.
A psychological, heart-wrenching love story that provides a
unique and inside look at Charles Darwin.
Torn between faith and science, he struggles to finish his legendary book "On the Origin of
the Species," which goes on to become the foundation for evolutionary biology.
Charles Darwin, played by Paul Bettany.
Emma Darwin, played by Jennifer Connelly.
Anne Darwin, played by Martha West.
Technician, played by Guy Henry.
John Brodie-Innes, played by Jeremy Northam.
Thomas Henry Huxley, played by Toby Jones.
Creation is a 2009 British biographical drama film about Charles Darwin's relationship with his wife Emma and
his memory of their eldest daughter Annie, as he struggles to write On the Origin of Species.
The film, directed by Jon Amiel and starring real life couple Paul Bettany and Jennifer Connelly as Charles and Emma
Darwin, is a somewhat fictionalised account based on Randal Keynes's Darwin biography Annie's Box.
The film explores themes of faith, biography, devoutness, author, evolution.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.